Furth, Josef Herbert; Papers ger036
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Josef Herbert Furth Papers
1932-1981
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger036
4.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence with Gottfried Haberler, Friedrich A. Hayek, Eric Voegelin, and other fellow Viennese Émigré economists, 1937–1981; typescripts of his reviews, articles, and papers, 1932–1981; lectures and course syllabi, 1942–1974; reports and reviews written for the U.S. Federal Reserve Board, 1944–1966; and offprints of articles. Furth taught economics at Catholic University and American University, wrote on central banking and international monetary relations, and was an economist for the Federal Reserve Board.
Biographical Sketch
Josef Herbert Furth was born on October 12, 1899 in Vienna, Austria. His father, Emil Ritter von Fürth (1863-1911), was a lawyer and a member of Vienna's City Council, who pioneered in school and housing reform, while his mother, born Ernestine Kisch (1877-1946), was the founder and leader of the Austrian women's suffrage movement.
Furth attended schools in Vienna and graduated from the Gymnasium with honors in 1917, and immediately enlisted as a reserve officer in the Austrian army. After being severely wounded, Furth was discharged in 1918 and entered into the study of law and social sciences at the Universities of Vienna and Heidelberg, Germany, receiving his J.D. degree from the University of Vienna in 1921. After serving as a law clerk for a number of years, Furth was admitted to the Austrian bar in 1929. With the exception of one year (1931-1932), which Furth spent in the United States as a Rockefeller Fellow in Social Science, primarily studying at the Yale Institute of Human Relations, Furth practiced law in Vienna until forced to leave in 1938.
Immediately after being discharged from the army, Furth, together with friend Friedrich A. (von) Hayek (Nobel-prize winner in economics), founded the Association of Democratic Students in an effort to combat the increasing right- and left-wing extremism among Vienna's students. In 1921, while still students, Furth and Hayek formed an informal circle of young social scientists, most of whom, like Furth and von Hayek, later emigrated to the United States. This group, which met for 16 ½ years included such international scholars as economists Gottfried von Haberler, Fritz Machlup and Oskar Morgenstern, political scientist Eric Voegelin, sociologist Alfred Schütz, philosopher Felix Kaufmann, historian Friedrich Engel-Janosi, art historians Otto Benesch and Johannes Wilde, and mathematician Karl Menger.
In the fall of 1938 (shortly after Austria's annexation to Germany), Furth immigrated to the United States. He became a "special student" at Harvard during the year 1938-1939, after which he was appointed professor of economics at Lincoln University in Pennsylvania.
In the spring of 1943, Furth was asked to join the staff of the Federal Reserve Board in Washington, D.C. as an economic specialist, with the specific assignment of preparing Handbooks on money and banking for various European and Asian countries to be liberated by the Allied Forces. Three years later he became a permanent member of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board, and in time advanced to Senior Advisor on international finance and associate economist of the Federal Open-Market Committee, the policy-making body of the Federal Reserve system.
In addition to his duties at the Federal Reserve, Furth was a part-time lecturer in economics at The Catholic University (1945-1950), The American University (1950-1968), the International University of Luxembourg (1960, as a visiting professor of international finance), and the School of Advanced International Studies of The Johns Hopkins University (1968-1969). In 1949 Furth was "seconded" to the World Bank to accompany the newly appointed U.S. Commissioner for Germany, McCloy, and brief him on West Germany's international financial problems and to write a report on these problems.
In 1966 Furth retired from the Federal Reserve and joined the Foreign Service Institute (whose economic division he had helped to organize) as Faculty Associate in Residence. After 1972 he served as Faculty Associate Emeritus, still being asked to give lectures on international finance and history of economic thought.
Furth was married to Emma P. Kann since 1929 and had two sons, Helmut F., a lawyer of Short Hills, New Jersey and New York, and Werner F., associate director of the Martin-Marietta Laboratories of Baltimore, Maryland. Furth died in Chevy Chase, Maryland on March 6, 1995.
1899 Born on Oct. 12 in Vienna, Austria; father Emil Ritter von Fürth (1863-1911), a leader of the social reform movement in Vienna; mother Ernestine Kisch (1877-1946), the founder and leader of Austria's women's suffrage movement.
1917 Graduated with honors from Gymnasium in Vienna; joined the Austrian army.
1918 Was severely wounded and discharged from the army; founded the Association of Democratic Students with Friedrich A. von Hayek.
1918-1923 Studied law and economics at the University of Vienna, Austria.
1920 Studied law at the University of Heidelberg, Germany.
1921 Received Doctor of Jurisprudence degree with honors from the University of Vienna.
1921-1922 Secretary of the Viennese Labor Conciliation Board (Einigungsamt).
1923-1938 Practiced law in Vienna.
1929 Marriage to Emma P. Kann; became a member of the Austrian Bar.
1931-1932 Spent one year in the United States on socio-legal research as a Rockefeller Fellow in Social Science.
1938 Emigrated to the United States.
1938-1939 Attended Harvard University as a Special Student.
1939-1943 Professor of Economics, Lincoln University, Lincoln, PA.
1943-1967 Served as an economic specialist at the Federal Reserve Board, Washington, D.C.
1945-1950 Lecturer at Catholic University, Washington, D.C.
1948-1952 Chief of the Eastern European and Near Eastern Section of the Federal Reserve Board.
1949 Served as Consultant to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.
1950-1966 Adjunct Professor (Lecturer) at The American University, Washington, D.C.
1952-1956 Chief of the Western European and Commonwealth Section of the Federal Reserve Board.
1956-1957 Chief of the International Financial Operations Section of the Federal Reserve Board.
1957-1960 Associate Adviser to the Federal Reserve Board.
1960 Visiting Professor, International University of Luxembourg.
1961-1964 Served as Adviser and Associate Economist to the Federal Open Market Committee of the Federal Reserve Board.
1964-1967 Consultant to the Federal Reserve Board.
1966 Retirement from the Federal Reserve Board.
1966-1974 Lecturer at the Foreign Service Institute.
1967-1968 Consultant to the State Department; staff member of the National Bureau of Economic Research.
March 6, 1995 Died in Chevy Chase, Maryland.
Scope and Contents
The J. Herbert Furth Papers, 1932-1981, focus on two major aspects of Furth's life, his years of service on the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board (1943-1966), and his years of both private lecturing and teaching at American universities.
The collection is divided into seven series: 1) Biographical materials, correspondence re: employment; 2) Correspondence, 1937-1981; 3) Foreign Dollar Balances -- Typescripts and correspondences, 1967-1973; 4) Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board, 1944-1966; 5) Typescripts and published versions of essays, speeches and position papers, 1932-1981; 6) Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors; and 7) Course and lecture notes, 1942-1974. The materials are primarily in English, with some early typescripts and publications in German.
The highlights of the collection are the large volume of correspondence spanning nearly four and a half decades with many prominent economists of the time period, including lengthy correspondences with Friedrich A. von Hayek, Fritz Machlup and Gottfried Haberler. Also represented in the collection is a nearly complete collection of Furth's official papers written as an Economist for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board, as well as his personal papers written for publication and lecturing events.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Biographical materials, correspondence re: employment, 1939-1974
Series 2: Correspondence, 1937-1981
Series 3: Foreign Dollar Balances -- Typescripts and correspondence, 1967-1973
Series 4: Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board, 1944-1966
Series 5: Typescripts and published versions of essays, speeches and position papers, 1932-1981
Series 6: Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors
Series 7: Course and lecture notes, 1942-1974
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Prof. J. Herbert Furth in February 1982.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Economics; International Women's Tribune Centre Collection.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Furth, J. Herbert (Joseph Herbert), 1899-; Haberler, Gottfried, 1900-1995.; Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Friedrich August), 1899-1992.; Machlup, Fritz, 1902-1983.; Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (U.S.)
- Biographical materials, correspondence re: employment, 1939-1974; 1; 22 folders
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists primarily of correspondence and contracts dealing with Furth's employment as an Economist at the Federal Reserve Board, and as a lecturer and professor at various U.S. universities, including Lincoln University in Pennsylvania, The American University and Catholic University in Washington, D.C., and the Foreign Service Institute in Washington, D.C. Also included in this series are several curriculum vitae and short biographical statements.
  - Address lists, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae, biographical statements, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 2)
  - List of publications, 1950-1969 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 3)
  - Memberships, certificates, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 4)
  - Photograph, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 5)
  - Retirement speech, 1967 January 10 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 7)
  - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Correspondence, 1943-1968 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 8)
  - Department of State. Appointment forms, contracts, 1966-1968 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 9)
  - Department of State. Correspondence, 1949-1974 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 10)
  - Foreign Service Institute. Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 11)
  - The American University. Correspondence, 1948-1966 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 12)
  - The Catholic University of America. Contracts, 1945; 1949 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 13)
  - Georgetown University, 1954-1960 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 14)
  - The Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies, 1960-1969 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 15)
  - Lincoln University, 1939-1959 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 16)
  - Senior Seminar on Foreign Policy, Foreign Service Institute, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 17)
  - SSRC Summer Research Training Institute, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 18)
  - Université Internationale de Sciences Comparées, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 19)
  - Verein für Alpenhotels GmbH, 1956-1963 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 20)
  - Oversize correspondence folders, 1.21
    - Hayek, Friedrich August von, 1937-1978 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 21)
    - Steff (=Martha Steffy Browne), 1972; 1980 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials, correspondence re: employm), Folder 22)
- Correspondence, 1937-1981; 2; 208 folders
  The largest part of the correspondence consists of correspondence with fellow economists, including a substantial amount with former Austrian émigrés Friedrich A. von Hayek, Gottfried Haberler, Fritz Machlup and Oscar Morgenstern. Also included among the correspondents are fellow economists from the Federal Reserve Board and other noted economists, such as: Frits J. de Jong, Alexander Gerschenkron, Ervin P. Hexner, Charles P. Kindleberger, Fred H. Klopstock, Miroslav Kriz, Arthur W. Marget, François Perroux, Walter S. Salant, Joseph Schumpeter, Wendell E. Thorne, Henry C. Wallich, C. Raymond Whittlesey, and Herbert T. Zassenhaus.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Alon, Gabriel, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Altman, Oscar L., 1958; 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - American Defense, Harvard Group, 1943-1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - American Economic Association (American Economic Review, Kenneth Boulding), 1940-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Ames, Edward, 1954-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Angell, James W., 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Anker, Wallace R., 1968-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Aschheim, Joseph, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - B -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Balough, Thomas, 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Barger, Harold, 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Bennett, Jack, 1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Beschoar, John M., 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Blumberg, Aryeh, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Bopp, Karl R., 1943-1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Borchardt, Knut, 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Briefs, Goetz, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Brown, William Adams, Jr. (The Brookings Institution), 1952-1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Bryant, Ralph, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - C, D - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - CDM (Coalition for a Democratic Majority; George C. Sponsler; Maria Thomas), 1974-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1951; 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Cohen, Benjamin J., 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Colm, Gerhard, 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Committee for Economic Development (Alfred C. Neal), 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Coombs, Charles A., 1953; 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Richard N., 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Coulbois, Paul, 1961-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Cover, John H., 1948-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Cozens, Winifred, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Craver, Earlene, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Crowther, Sir Geoffrey (The Economist), 1953; 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - de Iongh, D. Crena, 1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - de Jong, Frits J., 1960-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - de Mowbray, Guy, 1967-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Dembitz, Lewis, 1947-1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Deming, Frederick L., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Duisenberg, W. F., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Duncombe, Bruce F., 1970-1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Dupriez, Léon H., 1961-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - E, F -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Ehrlich, Edna E., 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Ellis, George H., 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Ellis, Howard S., 1950-1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Elrod, Warrick E., Jr. (Foreign Service Economic Studies), 1965-1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Emminger, Otmar (Deutsche Bundesbank), 1960-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Engel-Janosi, Friedrich, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Exter, John, 1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Fayette, Jacques R., 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Fisher, Allan G. B., 1964-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - FitzPatrick, Paul J., 1949-1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Fleming, J. Marcus, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - Foa, Bruno, 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - Fousek, Peter, 1957-1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1938-1939 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56)
  - Furth, Emma, 1938-1940 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 57)
  - Furth, Helmut J., 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 58)
  - Fürth, Wilhelmine von, 1940-1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - G -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - Gainsbrugh, Martin R. (National Industrial Conference Board, Inc), 1960-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - Garvy, George, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - Gemmill, Robert F., 1967-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - Gerschenkron, Alexander, 1950-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - Goldstein, Henry N., 1964-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - Gollwieser, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - Gragnani, Carlo, 1956-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - Graham, Frank D., 1940; 1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68)
  - Grossman, Gregory, 1949; 1956 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 69)
  - Grove, David L., 1952-1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - Gude, Gilbert, 1957; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - Gulick, Charles A., Jr., 1944 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 72)
  - H -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 73)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1951-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 74)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1961-1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 75)
  - Halm, George N., 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 76)
  - Handwörterbuch der Sozialwissenschaften, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 77)
  - Hansen, Alvin H., 1941; 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 78)
  - Harris, Seymour E., 1945-1946 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 79)
  - Harrod, Sir Roy, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 80)
  - Haugerud, Howard E., 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 81)
  - Havighurst, Clark C. (Law and Contemporary Problems), 1967-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 82)
  - Haythe, Madison H., 1961-1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 83)
  - Heatherington, Donald F., 1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 84)
  - Heginbetham, Erland, 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 85)
  - Hexner, Ervin P., 1950-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 86)
  - Higgins, Benjamin, 1949; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 87)
  - Hirsch, Julius, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 88)
  - Hoctor, Thomas F., 1970-1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 89)
  - Holland, Robert, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 90)
  - Holmes, Alan R., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 91)
  - Holtrop, Marius W., 1954; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 92)
  - J, K -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 93)
  - Jasny, Naum, 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 94)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1938 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 95)
  - Jones, Homer, 1967-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 96)
  - Journal of Economic History (Dorothy S. Brady), 1972-1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 97)
  - Kafka, Alexandre, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 98)
  - Kaplan, J. J. (Jack), 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 99)
  - Katz, Samuel I., 1967; 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 100)
  - Kaufmann, Felix, 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 101)
  - Kerschagl, Richard, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 102)
  - Kindleberger, Charles P., 1951-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 103)
  - Klopstock, Fred H., 1947-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 104)
  - Knapp, J. Burke, 1946-1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 105)
  - Knorr, Klaus, 1955 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 106)
  - Kriz, Miroslav, 1958-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 107)
  - Kronstein, Heinrich, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 108)
  - L -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 109)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 110)
  - Letiche, John M., 1955; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 111)
  - Lewis, Anthony, 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 112)
  - Liefmann-Keil, Elisabeth, 1959; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 113)
  - Livingston, J. A. (Joe), 1965-1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 114)
  - Logue, Ruth, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 115)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1938-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 116)
  - Mann, Fritz Karl, 1948 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 117)
  - Mann, Maurice, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 118)
  - Marget, Arthur W., 1941-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 119)
  - Marx, Daniel, Jr., 1955-1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 120)
  - Mason, Edward S., 1941; 1947 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 121)
  - Mason, Will E., 1959-1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 122)
  - Mayer, Helmut W., 1968-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 123)
  - Mayio, Albert, 1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 124)
  - McLaughlin, James A., 1941 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 125)
  - Mendershausen, Horst, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 126)
  - Menger, Karl, 1979; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 127)
  - Mintz, Ilse, 1970; 1973 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 128)
  - Mitchell, George W., 1965; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 129)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar, 1939; 1948; 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 130)
  - Mossé, Robert, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 131)
  - Mundell, Robert A. (Journal of Political Economy), 1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 132)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 133)
  - N, O, P -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 134)
  - Nelson, Charles J., 1949; 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 135)
  - Neumark, Fritz, 1960-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 136)
  - Newman, Monroe, 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 137)
  - Nurkse, Ragnar, 1949-1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 138)
  - Parker, William N., 1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 139)
  - Pauley, Bruce F., 1979 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 140)
  - Penninger, Philip E., 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 141)
  - Pennsylvania Business Survey (Alice Warne), 1962-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 142)
  - Perroux, François (Institut de Science Économique Appliquée), 1951-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 143)
  - Pizer, Samuel, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 144)